Inventory of the Luis Kutner papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- World Policy Planning Institute (Box 61)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 61: 2-3)
  - Henry Turkel, 1948-1967 (Box-folder 61: 4-5)
- World Public Order Court
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1949-1968 (Box-folder 61: 6-7)
  - Committee for the Study of Mankind, 1960
    Conference papers
- Habeas Corpus, 1962, and comments on Kutner's world habeas corpus proposal by Harold D. Lasswell, undated (Box-folder 61: 8)
- Human rights and world peace (Box 62)
  - American Society of International Law--Panel on International Human Rights Law and Its Implementation, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 62: 1-2)
  - World Peace through Law conference, Belgrade, Yugoslavia, 1971 (Box-folder 62: 3-4)
  - United Nations charter revision, 1970 (Box-folder 62: 5-7)
- Article about Luis Kutner, 1972 (Box-folder 63: 1)
- Great Britain and Ireland
  - Accounts of arrests, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 63: 2)
  - List of detainees, 1972 and undated (Box-folder 63: 3)
  - Petition, 1972 (Box-folder 63: 4)
    Photocopy
  - Case--William John Moore vs. R. Shillington, 1972 (Box-folder 63: 5)
  - Miscellany, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 63: 6)
- Association for Legal Justice, 1971 (Box-folder 63: 7-8)
  Clippings, printed matter, statement, and miscellany
- Sisters of the Holy Child Jesus, 1972 and undated (Box-folder 63: 9)
  Memoranda, report, and miscellany
- Council of Europe, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 63: 10)
  Clippings, letter, note, and miscellany
- American Society of International Law annual meeting, 1969-1971 and undated (Box-folder 63: 11-13)
  Bulletin, clippings, correspondence, memoranda, newsletter, notes, paper, and printed matter
- Printed matter on human rights and freedom, undated (Box-folder 63: 14)
- Articles about Luis Kutner, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 64: 1)
  Publicity
- Address and phone file, undated (Box-folder 64: 2)
- Printed matter, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 64: 3-4)
  Includes information on Campaign for Social Justice in Northern Ireland
- Records of cases, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 64: 5-8)
  Includes civil cases for damages, case of William James Close (Belfast), Heanley case (Ireland), and Brigid T. V. McDonnell case (Great Britain)
- Correspondence
  - Liam Clancy, 1972 (Box-folder 64: 9)
  - Eileen McEntee, 1971 (Box-folder 64: 10)
  - Irish Times, 1972 (Box-folder 64: 11)
  - Queen Elizabeth II, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 64: 12-13)
- Note on British judicial corruption, undated (Box-folder 64: 14)
- Internment orders, 1971 (Box-folder 64: 15)
- Irish Northern Aid Committee, 1971 (Box-folder 64: 16)
  Clipping and letter
- Mission to Northern Ireland, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 64: 17)
  Report by Luis Kutner
- Committee of 1000 for Irish Freedom, 1971 (Box-folder 64: 18)
  Letter and note
- Council of Europe, undated (Box-folder 64: 19-20)
  Article and miscellany
- International Commission of Jurists, 1972 (Box-folder 64: 21)
- International League for the Rights of Man, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 64: 22)
- Human rights, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 64: 23)
  Includes "A Proposal for a United Nations Writ of Habeas Corpus and an International Court of Human Rights" by Luis Kutner
- Clippings and printed matter relating to Civil Authorities Act (Northern Ireland), 1922; federal injunction in illegal search and unconstitutional police conduct (photocopy), 1968; convention on genocide, undated; and Compton report on legal consequences, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 64: 24-27)
- Iran, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 65: 1-4)
- Northern Ireland, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 65: 5)
- Petition submitted by Luis Kutner and Commission for International Due Process of Law to Elizabeth II, respondent, 1972 (Box-folder 65: 6)
- India (Box 66)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 66: 1-2)
  - Magazines and bulletins, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 66: 3)
  - All India Civil Liberties Council, 1959-1963 (Box-folder 66: 4)
  - India World Committee for Human Rights, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 66: 5)
    Article, printed matter, report, and statement
  - World Government for World Court, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 66: 6)
- Iraq, 1969 (Box-folder 66: 7)
- India (Box 67)
  - Correspondence with Ved Nanda, 1976 (Box-folder 67: 1)
  - Printed matter, 1947 (Box-folder 67: 2)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to the budget, estate planning, disarmament, individual rights, political issues, tax reforms, world peace, and related materials, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 67: 3-6)
- Miscellany, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 67: 7)
- Ghana--Miscellany, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 68: 1)
- Haiti--Miscellany, 1959-1976 (Box-folder 68: 2-3)
- India
  - Correspondence
    - Raj Jethmalani, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 68: 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1976 (Box-folder 68: 5)
  - Miscellany, 1975-1976 and undated (Box-folder 68: 6-9)
- Miscellany, 1970 (Box-folder 68: 10-11)
- Correspondence-- Jewish Post and Opinion, 1969 (Box-folder 69: 1)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to condition of Jews in different countries, genocide in Africa, human rights, Middle East crisis, women's rights, and related materials, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 69: 2-5)
- Miscellany, 1970 (Box-folder 69: 6)
  Materials relating to establishment of Illinois Committee for Soviet Jewry and printed matter
- Announcement, articles, and press release about Luis Kutner, 1972 (Box-folder 70: 1)
- Writings by Luis Kutner
  - "Burden of Proof," article, undated (Box-folder 70: 2)
  - Comments about the Latino community advocating Committee for Latino Public Justice, undated
  - Comments on the situation in Northern Ireland and the role of women in safeguarding freedom, undated
- Correspondence
  - James W. Morgan, 1972 (Box-folder 70: 3)
  - Gary Seewald, 1979 (Box-folder 70: 4)
  - Chester Leo Smith, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 70: 5)
  - M. Z. Souidan, 1966 (Box-folder 70: 6)
  - Freedom Center, 1972 (Box-folder 70: 7)
  - Miscellaneous (including Edmund G. Brown), 1965-1973 and undated (Box-folder 70: 8-9)
- Clippings and printed matter about Ireland, the Jewish community, and liberty and freedom, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 70: 10-13)
- World Habeas Corpus: Commission for International Due Process of Law, 1972 (Box-folder 70: 14)
  An appeal to restore human rights, note, and related materials
- Women of World for Individual Freedom, undated (Box-folder 70: 15)
  Information sheet and minutes of meeting
- World Freedom Centers for World Public Justice, undated (Box-folder 70: 16)
  Proposal
- Miscellany, 1972 (Box-folder 70: 17)
- Ireland (Box 71)
  - Correspondence
    - National Council of the Churches of Christ, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 71: 1)
    - Kotaro Tanaka, 1966-1974 (Box-folder 71: 2)
    - Kurt Waldheim, 1972 (Box-folder 71: 3)
    - Amnesty International, 1971 (Box-folder 71: 4)
    - Mario Biaggi, 1971 (Box-folder 71: 5)
  - Application and petition, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 71: 6)
  - Northern Ireland Act, 1972 (Box-folder 71: 7)
  - Committee for Foreign Affairs, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 71: 8)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 71: 9)
  - Collected articles, reports, and statements, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 71: 10)
  - Miscellany, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 71: 11)
- Statement by Luis Kutner before the House Foreign Affairs Committee, United States Congress, 1972 (Box-folder 72: 1)
- Correspondence
  - Leonard V. B. Sutton, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 72: 2)
  - H. W. Tambiah, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 72: 3)
  - Tan Sri Mohamed Suffian bin Hashim, 1974 (Box-folder 72: 4)
  - Hobart Taylor, 1964 (Box-folder 72: 5)
  - Telford Taylor, 1955-1971 (Box-folder 72: 6)
  - Virginia D. Taylor, 1960 (Box-folder 72: 7)
  - Helmut Schmidt, 1974 (Box-folder 72: 8)
  - Karl H. Beck, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 72: 9)
  - "T" miscellaneous, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 72: 10)
- Ireland
  - Article about Luis Kutner, 1972 (Box-folder 72: 11)
  - Correspondence
    - Amnesty International, 1972 (Box-folder 72: 12)
    - Anti-Slavery Society, 1972 (Box-folder 72: 13)
    - H. G. Kenelm, 1971 (Box-folder 72: 14)
      Includes 1 photographic print depicting "Rockwood House" (1870)
    - Richard J. Daley, 1972 (Box-folder 72: 15)
    - Michael Drexler, 1972 (Box-folder 72: 16)
    - Patrick Duffy, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 72: 17)
    - Thomas J. Farer, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 72: 18)
    - Brian Faulkner, 1971 (Box-folder 72: 19)
    - Bernard Frank, 1971 (Box-folder 72: 20)
    - Clifford Hackett, 1972 (Box-folder 72: 21)
    - Edward Heath, 1972 (Box-folder 72: 22)
    - H. Hannum Boyle, 1972 (Box-folder 72: 23)
    - John F. McCarthy, 1973 (Box-folder 72: 24)
    - Paul McKenna, 1972 (Box-folder 72: 25)
    - Reginald Maudling, 1971 (Box-folder 72: 26)
    - Karel Vasak, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 72: 27)
    - WBBM, 1972 (Box-folder 72: 28)
  - Miscellany, including materials on Council of Europe, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 72: 29-33)
- Correspondence (Box 73)
  - Haim Cohn, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 73: 1)
  - Frank Isaacs, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 73: 2)
  - Garson Kanin, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 73: 3)
  - Louis B. Sohn, 1976 (Box-folder 73: 4)
  - International Association of Democratic Lawyers, 1977 (Box-folder 73: 5)
  - International Law Society, 1971 (Box-folder 73: 6)
  - Life Magazine, 1958 (Box-folder 73: 7)
    Includes rough draft of an article by Louis Kutner, "International Court of Habeas Corpus and the United Nations Writ of Habeas Corpus"
  - Quincy Wright, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 73: 8)
  - Miscellany, 1969 (Box-folder 73: 9)
- Israel, 1969-1976 and undated (Box-folder 73: 10-12)
- Writings by Luis Kutner, 1969 (Box-folder 73: 13)
  Article about world habeas corpus
- Clippings and printed matter about environment, human rights Israel and the Arabs, and political scene in Europe and the United States, 1969-1978 (Box-folder 73: 14-15)
- Miscellany, 1969 (Box-folder 73: 16)
- Israel (Box 74)
  - Correspondence
    - Roger Baldwin, 1975 (Box-folder 74: 1)
    - Bernard Boodin, 1975 (Box-folder 74: 2)
    - John F. X. Irving, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 74: 3)
    - Julius Klein, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 74: 4)
    - Yitzhak Rabin, 1976 (Box-folder 74: 5)
    - Hirsch L. Silverman, 1976 (Box-folder 74: 6)
    - Jacob K. Javits, 1976 (Box-folder 74: 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 74: 8)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 74: 9-11)
  - Miscellany, 1970-1976 and undated (Box-folder 74: 12-16)
    Includes speech by Chaim Herzog and memorandum by Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn
- Israel (Box 75)
  - Correspondence
    - Anita Diamant, 1976 (Box-folder 75: 1)
    - Harrison A. Williams, Jr., 1976 (Box-folder 75: 2)
  - Research materials, 1976 (Box-folder 75: 3-4)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1976 (Box-folder 75: 5-7)
  - Application by Israel to the International Court of Justice, undated (Box-folder 75: 8)
  - Miscellany, 1976 and undated (Box-folder 75: 9-10)
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box-folder 76: 1)
  - "International Law Basis of International Due Process for Prisoners of War,", undated
  - "The Commission for International Due Process of Law and the International Action Commission,", undated
- Israel
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1960-1969 (Box-folder 76: 2-4)
  - Adolf Eichmann, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 76: 5-8)
  - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 76: 9)
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box 77)
  - "The Commission for International Due Process of Law and the International Action Commission,", undated (Box-folder 77: 1)
  - "World Habeas Corpus and the Commission for International Due Process of Law,", undated (Box-folder 77: 2)
- Correspondence
  - Haim Cohn, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 77: 3-4)
  - Joseph P. Sternstein, 1975 (Box-folder 77: 5)
  - Morrie Rotman, 1976 (Box-folder 77: 6)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to American and Russian politics, anti-Semitism, the environment, Israel and Zionism, and the Palestinian issue, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 77: 7-9)
- Correspondence (Box 78)
  - Andrei Amalrik, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 78: 1)
  - Blazo Jovanovic, 1974 (Box-folder 78: 2)
  - Justice, 1968 (Box-folder 78: 3)
  - Max M. Kampelman, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 78: 4)
  - Mahmoud Ali Kasuri, 1965 (Box-folder 78: 5)
  - "K" miscellaneous, 1963-1973 (Box-folder 78: 6)
  - Larry P. McDonald, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 78: 7)
- Clippings and printed matter
  - Israel, 1952-1969 (Box-folder 78: 8-10)
  - Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 78: 11)
- Press release about Luis Kutner's proposal to establish an International Psychiatry Commission, 1965 (Box-folder 79: 1)
- Correspondence
  - B. R. L. Iyengar, 1963 (Box-folder 79: 2)
  - International Commission of Jurists, 1959-1963 (Box-folder 79: 3)
  - International Commission for Political Asylum, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 79: 4)
  - M. Szatmary--The First International Congress of Jewish Lawyers and Jurists, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 79: 5)
  - Alfred De Grazia, 1965 and undated (Box-folder 79: 6)
  - Frank J. Filippi, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 79: 7)
  - International Red Cross, 1965 (Box-folder 79: 8)
  - Nathan Jacobs, 1967 (Box-folder 79: 9)
  - Japan Federation of Bar Association, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 79: 10)
  - Jacob K. Javits, 1964-1970 (Box-folder 79: 11)
  - Jack P. Jefferies, 1971 (Box-folder 79: 12-13)
  - Albert E. Jenner, Jr., 1969 (Box-folder 79: 14)
  - George Jessel, 1972 (Box-folder 79: 15)
  - John K. Jessup, 1961-1967 (Box-folder 79: 16)
  - Lyndon B. Johnson, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 79: 17)
  - Roger M. Johnson, 1968 (Box-folder 79: 18)
  - "J" miscellaneous, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 79: 19)
- Samuel Bankole Jones, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 79: 20-21)
  Clippings, letters, and report
- International Psychiatry--Alex Sandri White, 1957-1965 and undated (Box-folder 79: 22-25)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to international conciliation, the International Commission for Justice, and the International Criminal Court, 1967-1971 and undated (Box-folder 79: 26-28)
- Correspondence (Box 80)
  - Paul G. Hoffman, 1964-1973 (Box-folder 80: 1)
  - Herbert Hoover, 1962 (Box-folder 80: 2)
  - Leonard Horwin, 1967-1978 (Box-folder 80: 3-4)
  - Ti Hsiao, 1963-1968 (Box-folder 80: 5)
  - Hudson Institute, 1968 (Box-folder 80: 6)
  - John Humphrey, 1965 (Box-folder 80: 7)
  - Fanny Hurst, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 80: 8)
  - Eitizaz Hussain, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 80: 9)
  - Robert M. Hutchins, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 80: 10)
  - James Nevins Hyde, 1955 (Box-folder 80: 11)
  - Philip H. Idkowiak, 1971 (Box-folder 80: 12)
  - "I" miscellaneous, 1965 (Box-folder 80: 13)
- Writing by Luis Kutner--Article, "To Make Freedom Real,", undated (Box-folder 80: 14)
- International Bar Association, 1955-1969 (Box-folder 80: 15-19)
  Brochure, bulletin, clippings, correspondence, printed matter, and resolution regarding world habeas corpus
- Correspondence (Box 81)
  - Chicago Bar Association, 1950 (Box-folder 81: 1)
  - Eleanor Steinert, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 81: 2)
  - Adlai E. Stevenson, III, 1962-1970 (Box-folder 81: 3)
  - Joseph W. Still, 1958-1968 (Box-folder 81: 4)
  - Colby Stilson, 1964 (Box-folder 81: 5)
  - Robert Gerald Storey, 1956 (Box-folder 81: 6)
  - Julius Stulman, 1973 (Box-folder 81: 7)
  - United States Department of State, 1960-1968 (Box-folder 81: 8-9)
- Cuba, 1978 (Box-folder 81: 10)
  Information sheet from the United States Department of State
- El Salvador, 1977 (Box-folder 81: 11)
  Clippings, letter, printed matte, and miscellany
- Commission for International Due Process of Law, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 81: 12-13)
  Sponsorship solicitation
- Douglas E. Stephens, 1955-1962 (Box-folder 81: 14)
  Articles, clippings, letters, receipts, and miscellany
- Correspondence (Box 82)
  - Benjamin B. Ferencz, 1980 (Box-folder 82: 1)
  - Leonard Schroeter, 1971 (Box-folder 82: 2)
  - Egon Schwelb, 1962-1970 (Box-folder 82: 3-4)
  - M. Seara-Vasquez, 1963 (Box-folder 82: 5)
  - Secretariat of the United States, 1961-1968 (Box-folder 82: 6)
    Includes a letter to U. Thant
  - Kenichi Sekine, 1967 (Box-folder 82: 7)
  - U.S. Senators--J. W. Fulbright, Edith Nourse Rogers, Sam J. Ervin, Jr., Jacob K. Javits, Marshall Korshak, Alexander Wiley, Clifford P. Case, John Sparkman, Lewis G. Odom, Jr., and John W. Bricker, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 82: 8)
  - Whitney North Seymour, 1959-1963 (Box-folder 82: 9)
  - Samuel H. Shapiro, 1968 (Box-folder 82: 10)
  - Lord Shawcross, 1964-1967 (Box-folder 82: 11)
  - Florence Perlow Shientag, 1968 (Box-folder 82: 12)
  - Hirsch Lazaar Silverman, 1979 (Box-folder 82: 13)
  - Dykes A. Simmons, Jr., 1966-1969 (Box-folder 82: 14)
  - Caroline K. Simon, 1959-1973 (Box-folder 82: 15)
  - Michael Singer, 1979 (Box-folder 82: 16)
  - Edwin M. Slote, 1961-1972 (Box-folder 82: 17-18)
    Includes an article by Luis Kutner, "World Habeas Corpus," undated
  - George Smathers, 1966 (Box-folder 82: 19)
  - William Snedden, 1965 (Box-folder 82: 20)
  - Louis B. Sohn, 1958-1965 (Box-folder 82: 21)
  - South and Central America, 1966 (Box-folder 82: 22)
- Scrapbook, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 82: 23)
- Miscellany, 1966-1975 and undated (Box-folder 82: 24-26)
- Correspondence (Box 83)
  - "S" miscellaneous, 1965-1974 (Box-folder 83: 1)
  - Mary Roebling, 1968-1977 (Box-folder 83: 2)
  - O. John Rogge, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 83: 3)
  - Miriam Rooney, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 83: 4)
  - Elliott Roosevelt, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 83: 5-7)
  - Roscoe Pound Law School--William F. Kennedy, 1966 (Box-folder 83: 8)
  - Leo Rosten, 1954-1963 (Box-folder 83: 9)
  - Morris B. Rotman, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 83: 10)
  - Julio Cueto Rua, 1964 (Box-folder 83: 11)
  - Sarge Ruck, 1969 (Box-folder 83: 12)
  - Mark Rudd, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 83: 13)
  - Dean Rusk, 1964 (Box-folder 83: 14)
  - Richard B. Russell, 1961 (Box-folder 83: 15)
  - Gustavo Salgado, 1954-1972 (Box-folder 83: 16)
  - William D. Saltiel, 1960 (Box-folder 83: 17)
  - M. C. Sansoni., 1966 (Box-folder 83: 18)
  - J. Anthony Kline, 1978 (Box-folder 83: 19)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to Israel, 1970-1979 (Box-folder 83: 20-21)
- Correspondence (Box 84)
  - Roscoe Pound, 1957-1964 (Box-folder 84: 1)
  - Pope Paul VI, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 84: 2)
  - Daulat Ram Prem, 1962-1966 (Box-folder 84: 3)
  - Violet Rawnsley, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 84: 4)
    Includes 3 unidentified photographic prints
  - David Rawnsley, 1962-1974 (Box-folder 84: 5)
  - J. Rea, Mr. and Mrs., and Mr. and Mrs. G. W. Meaker, 1977 (Box-folder 84: 6)
  - Michael Reisman, 1974-1980 (Box-folder 84: 7)
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1960-1969 (Box-folder 84: 8-9)
  - Peter W. Rodino, Jr., 1976 (Box-folder 84: 10)
  - Hassan Kamel, 1965 (Box-folder 84: 11)
  - Roman Pucinski, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 84: 12)
  - Miscellaneous "R", 1967-1973 (Box-folder 84: 13)
- Clippings and printed matter, including Luis Kutner's office and publicity materials, 1965-1980 (Box-folder 84: 14-15)
- King Peter II, 1963-1974 (Box-folder 84: 16)
  Biographical data on Luis Kutner and a speech by Kutner, clippings, letters, program, and miscellany
- Correspondence (Box 85)
  - Leslie Paffrath, 1971 (Box-folder 85: 1)
  - Shabtai Rosenne, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 85: 2)
  - Ferdinand Pecora, 1964 (Box-folder 85: 3)
  - Charles H. Percy, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 85: 4-5)
  - Herbert Phillips, 1967-1979 (Box-folder 85: 6)
  - Basil J. Photos, 1976 (Box-folder 85: 7)
  - International League for the Rights of Man, 1966 (Box-folder 85: 8)
  - "P" miscellaneous, 1965-1974 (Box-folder 85: 9-11)
- Greece and Cyprus
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box-folder 85: 12)
  - Clippings, printed matter, and miscellany, 1960-1979 (Box-folder 85: 13-20)
- Miscellany, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 85: 21-22)
  Includes information on Pope John Paul II and a petition requesting intervention by the Shah of Iran in a case involving Iranian interests, 1976-1979
- Great Britain and Northern Ireland (Box 86)
  - Correspondence
    - Mario Biaggi, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 86: 1)
    - Kevin Boyle, 1973 (Box-folder 86: 2)
    - A. B. McNulty, 1973 (Box-folder 86: 3)
    - Peter Rawlinson, 1973 (Box-folder 86: 4)
    - World Policy Committee, 1973 (Box-folder 86: 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1973 (Box-folder 86: 6)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1970-1978 (Box-folder 86: 7-8)
  - Miscellany, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 86: 9-12)
- Writings by Luis Kutner--Article, "World Freedom Centers and the World Public Order Court,", undated (Box-folder 86: 13)
- Ireland (Box 87)
  - Writings by Luis Kutner (Box-folder 87: 1)
    - "The Role of the Special Powers Act in the Protestant Ascendancy of Northern Ireland,", undated
    - Mission to Northern Ireland, 1972 (Box-folder 87: 2)
      Report
  - Correspondence
    - H. K. Harris, 1971 (Box-folder 87: 3)
    - WBBM, 1972 (Box-folder 87: 4)
    - World Policy Committee, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 87: 5)
    - Harold Lasswell, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 87: 6)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 87: 7-11)
  - Miscellany, 1972 (Box-folder 87: 12-15)
- Ireland (Box 88)
  - Writing by Luis Kutner, 1972 (Box-folder 88: 1)
    Report of his visit to Northern Ireland
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 88: 2-4)
  - European Commission of Human Rights--A. B. McNulty, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 88: 5-9)
  - Miscellany, 1970-1972 and undated (Box-folder 88: 10-11)
- Correspondence (Box 89)
  - Harold Lasswell, 1955-1974 (Box-folder 89: 1-4)
  - Leonard H. Marks, 1978 (Box-folder 89: 5)
  - Andrew Lee, 1971 (Box-folder 89: 6)
  - Warren Leslie, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 89: 7)
  - Howard S. Levie, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 89: 8)
  - Seymour D. Lewis, 1965 (Box-folder 89: 9)
  - Library of International Relations, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 89: 10)
  - Life Magazine, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 89: 11-12)
  - Max Heckmeyer, 1976 (Box-folder 89: 13)
  - Steven Henriques, 1971 (Box-folder 89: 14)
  - Edward E. Henry, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 89: 15-16)
  - Christian A. Herter, 1960 (Box-folder 89: 17)
  - Christopher Hills, 1965-1977 (Box-folder 89: 18)
- Miscellany--Chicago Medical School, undated (Box-folder 89: 19)
- Correspondence (Box 90)
  - Jeremiah Kerner, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 90: 1)
  - Charles J. Kersten, 1963 (Box-folder 90: 2)
  - Alan King and Harry Adler, 1968 (Box-folder 90: 3)
  - Marie Klinko, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 90: 4-6)
  - Ordre Souverain de Saint Jean de Jerusalem, 1968 (Box-folder 90: 7)
  - Alan Koehler, 1973 (Box-folder 90: 8)
  - Susan Kovats, 2002? (Box-folder 90: 9)
  - S. P. Kundra, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 90: 10)
  - Irv Kupcinet, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 90: 11)
  - Stephan Kutner, 1964 (Box-folder 90: 12)
  - Robert Lamarr, 1970 (Box-folder 90: 13)
  - Sara S. Landis, 1964-1971 (Box-folder 90: 14)
  - C. T. Lanham, 1957-1972 (Box-folder 90: 15)
  - Arthur Larson, 1958-1967 (Box-folder 90: 16)
  - "L" miscellaneous, 1959-1973 (Box-folder 90: 17)
- Miscellany, 1954-1962 (Box-folder 90: 18)
  Kutner College
- Environment/Whales (Box 91)
  - Correspondence
    - Hans Kelsen, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 91: 1)
      Includes 1 photographic print depicting Kelsen, undated
    - Miscellany, 1977 (Box-folder 91: 2)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 91: 3-4)
  - Reports, 1975-1977 and undated (Box-folder 91: 5)
- Oceanography, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 91: 6)
- John F. Kennedy, 1961-1968 (Box-folder 91: 7)
- Miscellany, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 91: 8)
- Whales (Box 92)
  - Correspondence
    - Kenneth S. Norris, 1977 (Box-folder 92: 1)
    - Harold Oram, 1977 (Box-folder 92: 2)
    - Joyce Foundation, 1977 (Box-folder 92: 3)
    - Charles H. Percy, 1977 (Box-folder 92: 4)
    - National Geographic Society, 1977 (Box-folder 92: 5-6)
    - William Kardish and Melvin M. Payne re: World Court of Public Opinion, 1977 (Box-folder 92: 7)
    - Miscellany, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 92: 8)
  - Writing by Luis Kutner--Article, "The Genocide of Whales: A Crime against Humanity,", undated (Box-folder 92: 9)
  - Clippings and printed matter relating to the Whale Defense Center, whale defense fund, and world court of public opinion, 1972-1978 (Box-folder 92: 10-12)
- World Service Authority--Commission for International Due Process of law, undated (Box-folder 92: 13)